314 N Duncan St, Apt 6, Stillwater, OK

□ 405-762-0337 | ■ nikhil.gunti@okstate.edu | 回 nikhilgunti | 面 gunti-nikhil/

### Professional Summary \_

Business acumen with 3+ years of experience in product development domain having hands-on SQL, Python, R, and other technologies. Strong working knowledge on performing statistical data analysis by developing Tableau dashboards & running machine learning models.

### Education

#### Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK

CGPA: 3.91

MASTERS IN BUSINESS ANALYTICS & DATA SCIENCE

Aug. 2019 - May. 2021

JNTUH College of Engineering, Hyderabad, India

CGPA: 3.5

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Aug. 2013 - May. 2017

## Technical Skills & Certifications

- Programming Languages: C/C++, SAS, SQL, R, Python, Matlab, Verilog, Frameworks: Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch
- Tools: Alteryx, R Studio, Tableau, JMP, Power BI, Postgre SQL, Visual Studio, AWS, MS Azure, PySpark
- Certifications: Computer Vision NanoDegree Udacity, NLP & Deep Learning Specializations Deep Learning.ai, SAS Programmer
- Scholarships: National Science Foundation(NSF) I-Corps CIE Scholar 2020

# Work Experience\_

**Concat Systems** Dallas, TX

DATA SCIENCE INTERN May. 2020 - Present

- · Working on Cars metadata fine-grained recognition along with Blur detection & Image enhancement techniques
- · Implemented various object detection algorithms and tried DeepSORT algorithm to detect/track 20 custom objects in a video
- Developed production-level code using OpenCV CSRT/MOSSE to track a custom scratch/dent on cars 360' rotation videos

#### Computer Vision & Understanding Lab - CS Dept, OSU

Stillwater, OK

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May. 2020 - Present

- · Associated with Professor Dr. Sathyanarayanan Aakur on Computer Vision research Understanding visual world beyond recognition or captions without human supervision by developing self-supervised predictive learning for video event segmentation
- Working on paper Learning Temporal Compositional Representation of Videos for ICCV 2021

Wipro Limited Hyderabad, India

PRODUCT ENGINEER

Aug. 2017 - Jul. 2019

- Data Analytics Ran Naive Bayes & logistic regression models for multi-class text classification based on case description. Also, analyzed the factors behind lease cases and tried to predict the number of lease issues for next quarter.
- Consulting -Assisted clients with both functional & technical issues of the product TRIRIGA, specifically lease accounting of product
- Case Resolution Debugged platform & application issues of product and resolved 234 client cases in a year (2nd in team of 19)
- · Led a team of 3 experienced professionals and developed 8.5 hours of training content from the scratch solitary

### **Publications**.

- Accepted paper "Benchmark and Evaluation of Low Resource Object Detection in Biomedical Images" at AIPR 2020
- Under review "Knowledge Guided Learning: Moving towards Open Domain Egocentric Action Recognition with Zero Supervision"-PRL

# **Academic Projects**

### Fault Diagnosis in steel plates using Machine Learning

OSU

DATA ANALYST

Feb. 2020 - Apr. 2020 • Executed feature selection using PCA to identify variables involving pattern recognition and fault classification in steel plates

- Evaluated classification performance on SVM, Neural Networks, Random Forest, SGDClassifier and derived important variables in
- determining faults beforehand, thereby optimizing product testing cost & enhancing production quality

**MetroTech Center Retention** 

DATA ANALYST Aug. 2019 - Nov. 2019

- · Identified a list of factors contributing to overall student satisfaction(pattern) by analyzing 5 yrs of student survey responses
- · Interesting correlations between the variables influencing retention rate were drawn for further analysis
- · Built various ML models & interactive dashboards to analyze the drop-out pattern and provided strong recommendations

#### **Customer Feedback Analysis of Apple Products**

OSU

OSU

 Scraped data from Twitter & other social media websites and performed web content mining to analyze user's feedback on recently launched Apple iPhones. Used libraries like NLTK, Gensim to perform sentiment analysis & named entity of customer reviews

# Leadership & Management Roles.

- President: My role as President for Business Analytics Student Association (BASA) includes organizing technical workshops by industry leaders, meetups/fun-activities, ensuring cultural diversity, assisting BASA members for internship/job opportunities
- Community Development Volunteer: Worked with 'YouthForSeva' to stabilize the financial status of impoverished kids in public schools by enabling them to bag scholarships and conducted career empowerment sessions & weekend classes on maths and science